sonicstate.com 2019-07-04

# Sonicstate.com Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

We are committed to safeguarding the privacy of visitors to our website.

**1\. What information do we collect?**  
We may collect, store and use the following kinds of personal data:

Information about your visits to and use of this website.

  * information about any transactions carried out between you and us on or in relation to this website, including information relating to any purchases you make of our goods or services

  * information that you provide for the purpose of registering with us and subscribing to our email notifications.

  * and any other content you submit to us via the website or our services (collectively, “Your Content”), such as comments, enquiries, marketing preferences, and other information concerning your use of the website or our services.

**2\. Information about website visits**  
We may collect information about your computer and your visits to this website such as your IP address, geographical location, browser type, referral source, length of visit and number of page views. We may use this information in the administration of this website, to improve the website usability, and for marketing purposes.

We use cookies on this website. A cookie is a text file sent by a web server to a web browser, and stored by the browser. The text file is then sent back to the server each time the browser requests a page from the server. This enables the web server to identify and track the web browser.

We may send a cookie which may be stored on by your browser on your computer  hard drive. We may use the information we obtain from the cookie in the administration of this website, to improve the website  usability and for marketing purposes. We may also use that information to recognise your computer when you visit our website, and to personalise our website for you.  

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies. (For example, in Internet Explorer you can refuse all cookie by clicking “Tools”, “Internet Options”, “Privacy”, and selecting “Block all cookies” using the sliding selector.) This may, however, have a negative impact upon the usability of many websites, including this one.

 **Analytics**  
We use Google Analytics to provide us with general statistics about our visitors, they use cookies to allow us to see how visitors to our website are using it. We have set the data retention to 26 Months. 

**3\. Using your personal data**  
Personal data submitted on this website or through our services will be used for the purposes specified in this privacy policy or in relevant parts of the website.

  *  improve your browsing experience by personalising the website;
  *  send information (other than marketing communications) to you which we think may be of interest to you by post or by email or similar technology;
  *  send to you marketing communications relating to our business which we think may be of interest to you by email or similar technology (you can inform us at any time if you no longer require marketing communications to be sent by emailing us at enq@sonicstate.com);
  *  to generally run and improve the website and our services.

We will not without your express consent provide your personal information to any third parties for the purpose of direct marketing.

**4\. Antispam Policy**  
Newsletter Subscriber  
A user is added to our Newsletter Subscribers database when he/she subscribes to the newsletter, either by entering the email address in the subscribe box on all our pages, or by opting in at the checkout stage for any of our digital products. The process is a double opt-in, with an email containing a confirmation link which must be clicked in order to continue the signup process. An unsubscribe link is included in all communications.

What Is Spam?  
Spam is unsolicited email also known as Unsolicited Commercial Email (UCE). It involves emails sent to users who:

  * Have no association with the sender
  * Have registered an account but not opted in to receive commercial emails
  * Have previously opted in but then opted out of receiving commercial emails

Email Communications  
Sonicstate does  not send spam. Our emails are sent to inform subscribers of new content we post, products we sell and other related information.  Our Newsletters include the links to our news articles and videos, information about promotions and latest news from our industry.

We cooperate with other businesses that target similar audiences as ours - they send our newsletters to their opted-in subscriber base. We are very careful about the antispam practices of these businesses and never cooperate with companies that are outside the scope of our audience or our industry or which have an unclear Antispam Policy. On rare occasions we also send selected partners’ emails to our subscriber base.

We do not sell or distribute (for financial gain or for free) or otherwise disclose any partner or customer e-mail addresses to any third parties except when legally required.

Every newsletter contains an Unsubscribe link at the top of the message.

Necessary Communication  
There are situations which require us to send you emails. These include:

  * Sending a message to your emailbox with the link to activate your subscription to our newsletter at Sonicstate.com
  * Sending you invoices or links for product downloads for each completed transaction on our website.
  * Sending you emails concerning technical, legal and support matters.

Please make sure you do not flag Sonicstate  as ‘Spam’ or ‘Unsolicited’ in your email application. When you register and do not find an activation email in your inbox, check your spam folder.

When you get in contact with us (for example by email or via a form on the website) we will keep records of what is communicated.  This is to ensure we have a record of our discussion for future reference and so we can improve the website.

**5\. Cookies, Beacons and Tracking**  
Our website uses ‘cookies’ and similar technologies. Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer and mobile device by software that you install. They are widely used in order to make websites work, or work more efficiently, as well as to provide information to the owners of the site. Cookies may also be stored in your internet browser by or on behalf of third parties, such as Google or providers of advertising services.

We use cookies/beacons in the following ways:  
**Preferences**  
To remember information about you such as your preferred language and configuration.  
**Analytics**  
To help us understand how you use our website and services, and how often, so we can improve them to deliver a better experience for our users. To carry out research and statistical analysis to help improve our content, products and services.  
**Retargeting**  
We may use cookies to display advertisements to you about products and services we offer, which we think will be of interest to you based upon your previous use of our Website.  
We use analytics to collect and store anonymous statistical data about our users’ use of the website. Some of the cookies we use are essential for parts of the website to operate and have already been set. You may delete and block all cookies, but parts of the website may not work properly.

We may also collect information about your computer, mobile phone (or other portable or static device used to access the website) and your visit to the website, including where available your IP address, operating system, device name, screen name and browser type, for system administration and to report aggregate information to our partners and if necessary our advertisers.

We may use other technologies such as pixel tags, clear GIFs and web beacons on the website.

For more information about cookies, please visit allaboutcookies.org.  If you do not wish for us to use cookies when you use the Website, please adjust your Internet browser settings to decline cookies (your computer’s help documentation should tell you how to do this).  If you choose to decline cookies, some parts of the website may not work properly. By using the website, you agree to our use of cookies as described above.

If you want to learn about how to opt out of Google’s use of cookies, please visit <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/> or your Google Ads Settings ([www.google.com/settings/ads](https://www.google.com/settings/ads)). The Google Analytics terms of service can be accessed here: [www.google.co.uk/analytics/terms/us.html](https://www.google.co.uk/analytics/terms/us.html).

**6\. Other disclosures**  
In addition to the disclosures reasonably necessary for the purposes identified elsewhere in this privacy policy, we may disclose information about you:

  * to the extent that we are required to do so by law;
  * in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings;
  * in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights (including providing information to others for the purposes of fraud prevention and reducing credit risk);

If we buy or sell, or are negotiating the purchase or sale, of any business or assets, in which case your personal information may be shared with the purchaser or seller for that purpose.

We may anonymise information about you (so that you cannot be identified from it by third parties) and provide that information to third parties for the purposes of marketing analysis or to market the website or our services (for example, by letting our business partners know that 50 male individuals from a particular country viewed their product during a particular time period.

Except as provided in this privacy policy, we will not provide your information to third parties.

**7\. International data transfers**  
Information that we collect may be stored and processed in and transferred between any of the countries in which we operate in order to enable us to use the information in accordance with this privacy policy.

By submitting your information you agree to our use of the data as described in this privacy policy. This includes transferring your data to, and storing it at, a destination outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”).

**8\. Security of your personal data**  
We will take reasonable precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of your personal information. Of course, data transmission over the Internet is inherently insecure, and we cannot guarantee the security of data sent over the Internet

We will store all the personal information you provide on our secure servers. All electronic transactions you make to or receive from us will be encrypted using SSL technology.

**9\. Policy amendments**  
We may update this privacy policy from time-to-time by posting a new version on our website. You should check this page occasionally to ensure you are happy with any changes.

**10\. Your rights**  
You may instruct us to provide you with any personal information we hold about you.

You may instruct us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. In practice, you will usually either expressly agree in advance to our use of your personal data for marketing purposes, or we will provide you with an opportunity to opt-out of the use of your personal data for marketing purposes. You can also instruct us not to use your personal data for marketing purposes by email (to enq@sonicstate.com) at any time.

**11\. Third party websites**  
The website contains links to other websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of third party websites.

**12\. Financial Information**  
The website does not store your credit card and payment details on our server. Financial transactions are handled by reputable third party payment processors

**13\. Contact**  
If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our treatment of your personal data, please write to us by email to enq@sonicstate.com or by post to:

Sonic State Limited  
Unit 6 Brassmill Enterprise Centre  
Brassmill Lane  
Bath, BA1 3JN  
BANES

Tel: +44 (0) 1225 442546  
Email: enq@sonicstate.com
